Hey there!
哈喽
Happy New Year!
新年好
Are you still in the dorm?
你还在宿舍
Why didn't you tell me?
怎么不早说
I'm also home alone.
我也自己一个人在家呢
Actually, I didn't go back home
其实我今天为了复习
'cause I'm busy studying.
也没回老家
Aren't you with your family?
你没和家人一起过年吗
My dad is on a business trip.
我爸出差去了还没回呢
My mom is on vacation abroad.
我妈正在国外度假
They actually
他们呢
wanted me to join
居然让我跟家里那些
those distant relatives.
七大姑八大姨一块
I'm definitely not going!
我才不去呢
Wait for me.
等着我
I'm coming for you.
我现在来找你
OK.
好
So this is what the beach looks like
原来过年的时候
during the New Year.
海滩长这样
What you up to?
你干吗
I wanna...
我想
It's cold, don't.
水太冷别下去
But I wanna get closer to the sea,
可我想离海近一点
and splash around a bit.
踏踏浪
Come on.
上来
There!
我要去那儿
Is it cold?
冷不冷呀
Your ears feel cool.
冰冰的
You know what?
你知道吗
When I was a kid,
我小时候啊
watching Korean shows,
看韩剧的时候
I always saw
我总看到
the male lead carrying the female lead
男主角背着女主角
walking along the beach.
在海滩边走啊走
These are all typical tropes.
这都是固定桥段
I never thought that one day
没想到有一天
I could enjoy something like this.
我也能过上这种好日子
I remember we
我记得咱们之前
watched a show before.
看过一部
What was it called again?
叫什么来着
Autumn in My...
蓝色生
Stop it!
你干吗
Are you so eager to find another girl?
你这么想我找下家吗
That show was a tragedy, right?
那部剧是个悲剧是吧
But I believe
但是我相信
we'll definitely not end up like that.
我们绝对不会像那样
You will be good,
你会好好地
and I will be good too.
我也会好好地
We will always
我们都会一直
be together.
一直在一起
Never apart.
永远不分开
This is the first time I've seen
我也是第一次见
an empty beach.
没有人的沙滩
Everyone's home celebrating the New Year.
大家都在家过年
Tell me,
你说
when will the two of us
咱们两个什么时候
have our own home?
能有个小家呀
Qi Yu,
齐郁
if you're proposing to me
你要是以这种方式
this way,
跟我求婚
I won't agree.
我可不会答应
This is not a proposal.
我这哪是求婚呀
If I were to propose,
我要是真求婚
I would make it the most unique.
肯定是最特别的
Do you wanna
惟依
go to my home for the New Year next year?
明年要不要回我家过年
Careful.
慢点啊
Sorry.
不好意思啊
It's OK.
没
It's my parents.
我爸妈的电话
Would you like to talk to them?
要不聊两句
I'm good.
不了 不了
You
你
should say hi to them for me.
帮我跟叔叔阿姨问个好
Today is New Year's Eve.
今天是除夕夜
You three should
你们一家三口
have a talk.
好不容易说说话
I don't wanna be a third wheel.
我就不当显眼包了
I'll go have some fun on my own.
我自己去玩会儿
Qi Yu,
齐郁
you've really grown up now, huh?
你现在翅膀硬了
You don't wanna take
那在家里
the job we got for you at home,
给你找的工作你不干
but you have to stay so far away.
非跑那么远
You're not coming back for the New Year.
这过年了你也不回来
Everyone will ask
人家走家串户的
where you are
第一句就问
when they see us.
你儿子呢
Have you been drinking again?
你是不是又酒喝多了
No.
没有
Son,
儿子
no worries.
没事
Your dad is just worried about you,
你爸呀他就是担心你
afraid you're not doing well alone.
怕你一个人过得不好
What did you have for dinner?
今天年夜饭吃的什么呀
Aren't you with your friends?
没跟朋友一起过
Mom,
妈
I'm doing just fine here.
我在这边过得挺好的
And I will...
后面我还会继续
Your work there
你说你在那儿吧
is unstable,
工作工作不稳定
and you're not making much money.
钱钱挣不着
Your life feels like a game.
日子过得跟过家家似的
What's the point of getting a girlfriend?
找个女朋友有什么用
I don't think
我看你俩呀
you two can make it.
也成不了
Hey, it's a good day today!
大过年的
What the hack were you talking about?
你胡说八道什么
Dad.
爸
I...
我
Son,
儿子
forget it.
那要不就这样吧
It's the New Year's Eve.
大过年的
Have something nice to eat.
你多吃点好吃的
Call us when you have time.
有空常给我们打电话
Sure.
行
Mom, dad,
妈 爸
happy New Year!
新年快乐
Say something, you.
儿子跟你说新年快乐呢
Alright,
行了
let's hang up.
挂了吧
Happy New Year.
新年快乐
Come here!
快过来玩呀
Hurry!
快
Sit here.
快坐这儿
Let's see who can swing higher!
我们比谁荡得高
Who just shouted for me
谁刚才大言不惭地说
to pay for your cooking skills?
我出钱你出力
I thought you could whip up
我以为你能给我
a couple of nice dishes for me.
做俩硬菜出来呢
Now tell me what this is.
现在你告诉我这是什么
Food delivery?
外卖
If I'd like these, what do I need you for?
外卖我需要你点吗
You don't even
你平时在家里面
cook at home.
也不做饭
Your seasonings must be lacking.
那调味料肯定不全
I can't make it without ingredients.
我巧妇难为无米之炊啊
Alright.
行
Delivery is fine.
外卖你点就点了
What are you up to now?
你现在又在干什么
Plating the food?
摆盘
Is that necessary for only two of us?
有必要吗咱们就两个人
And we'll still have to
待会儿这些盘子
wash these plates later.
还都得洗
What I want is this vibe of abundance,
要的就是这种年年有余
a prosperous life.
生活富裕的气氛
Otherwise, why call it New Year?
要不怎么叫过年呢
Prosperity?
富裕
Don't you know if I'm prosperous or not?
我富不富裕你不知道啊
I can kiss New Year gifts goodbye again.
今年新年礼物又泡汤了
How beautiful!
多好看呀
Yeah,
是啊
you're really rolling in it now.
你都富得流油了
With that cabinet full of bags,
那一柜子的包
selling one would be
随便卖一个
enough for your debts.
都够抵债了
Selling?
卖我包我跟你讲
Zhao Fanggang, I'll kill you!
赵方刚我杀了你
Hurry,
快
repeat after me,
跟我说
pah, pah, pah!
呸 呸 呸
It was innocent talk.
童言无忌
Are you out of your mind?
有病吧你
You're over thirty!
三十多岁的人了
It was innocent talk.
童言无忌
Idiot!
神经病
Pah, pah, pah!
呸 呸 呸
It was innocent talk.
童言无忌
Fine, fine!
好 好 好
I'll say it, I'll say it!
我说 我说
I was wrong!
我错了
It was innocent talk.
童言无忌
Alright?
行了吧
Pah, pah, pah.
呸 呸 呸
There you go.
这就对了吗
OK.
好
It's the New Year.
过年吗
It's all about having a good time.
就是图个乐呵
We common folks,
也是咱普通老百姓
looking forward to the year ahead.
一年的盼头
No matter how much we make this year,
不管这一年收成如何
we have to stay cheerful.
都得乐呵呵地
That way, every day in the coming year
这样来年的每一天
will be safe
才能平安
and sound.
顺利
This skit
就这小品
is really entertaining!
特别有意思
Here we go.
来了 来了 来了
Why are you looking at me like that?
你干吗这么看我
Nothing.
没什么
It's just that
就是你刚才
the way you nagged
那个唠叨的劲儿
reminded me of my dad.
特别像我过世的爸
Besides these,
除了这些菜啊
I have a signature dish.
我还有个保留菜系
Yellow bean sprouts.
黄豆芽
Signature dish, yellow bean sprouts?
保留菜系 黄豆芽
Don't underestimate these sprouts.
你可别小瞧这黄豆芽
In my hometown, we eat these
我们老家过年啊
for New Year
过生日啊
and birthdays.
都会吃这个
They symbolize good fortune,
这豆芽形似如意
also known as "fortune vegetables".
也叫如意菜
Just wait,
等着
you're in for a treat.
我给你露一手
Alright.
行了
Leave it to me.
我来吧
I'm afraid you'll blow up my kitchen.
别把我家厨房炸了
Retard.
费劲
Dumplings are ready!
饺子来啦
Here.
来
Put them here.
放这儿 放这儿
I'm coming.
来了
Here, here.
来 来 来
Put them here.
放这儿
Careful.
烫
Yuheng's cooking skills
我这女婿的这个厨艺啊
are on par with mine.
越来越接近我了
Not just his cooking,
不光是厨艺
but also his mannerisms.
这个举手投足
He's starting to resemble the younger me.
都有我当年的风范了
Thanks.
谢谢
Oh, come on.
你得了吧你
Not to mention anything else,
你别说别的
just based on looks alone,
就单凭颜值这一点
you're nowhere near
你年轻的时候
as good-looking
那照小纪现在
as Yuheng is now.
那是差远了呀
Your mom pursued me back then.
你妈当年追的我
She said I looked
你妈说我长得
like that big star,
像那个大明星
Kris Phillips.
费翔
Right?
是不是
Yeah.
是
He is Kris Phillips.
人家是费翔吗
You're Kris Fat.
你是废物
Come on, dig in.
快吃 快吃 快吃
Time to eat.
吃饭
Try the dumplings!
尝尝饺子啊
Come on, have some of these.
亲家你多吃点啊
OK, OK.
好 好 好
The shrimps are so good.
这虾肉
It's the coin.
硬币
You found the coin in it!
吃到硬币了
This means
亲家你这
you're gonna have good luck!
你这要行大运
May you
新的一年
abundant fortune!
鸿福鸿运
We all hope to
我们大家到时候
share in your good fortune.
也都跟你沾沾光
Absolutely.
就是
That's wonderful!
太好了
Come on.
来 来 来
Let's make a toast.
借你们吉言了 碰一杯
In the new year...
新的一年啊
may us have great fortune!
行大运 行大运
Thanks.
谢谢 谢谢
Everything goes well.
事事顺利啊
Great fortune!
行大运
Thank you, Xiaoning.
谢谢你啊筱柠
You've brought so much
让我的生活
warmth to my life.
变得这么温暖
Ji Yuheng,
纪昱恒
thanks to you,
因为有你
my life
我的人生
feels so complete.
好像更圆满了
Happy New Year!
新年快乐
What's up?
怎么了
I'm taking over your spot.
过来抢你地盘呀
Your dumplings are good.
怎么包得这么好呀
You're trying to take my spot?
还想跟我抢地盘啊
Happy New Year,
新年快乐啊
Mr. Ji.
纪先生
Happy New Year.
新年快乐
I hope that in the future,
希望以后
we can celebrate
每一个春节
every new year together.
我们两个都可以一起过
Absolutely.
一定会的
Then it's settled!
那就这么说定了
Sure.
说定了
Looks great.
好看
I'll have one as well.
我也来一个
Seeing how affectionate they are,
照他们俩这个亲热劲啊
I think we'll be
我觉得咱们抱孙子
grandparents soon.
快了
You mentioned before
你那会儿跟我说
that they're living separately.
他们分房住
I was a bit worried back then.
我还真有点担心
But now it seems
现在看来
that worry
当初的担心
was unnecessary.
那都是多余的
Exactly.
就是
Now,
现在这样
this is how newlyweds
才是新婚小夫妻的
should be, right?
热乎劲儿吗
Yuheng
这小纪
has had feelings for Xiaoning for years.
喜欢筱柠这么多年
Now they're finally together.
也算是圆满了
How did you know that
昱恒喜欢筱柠
Yuheng has had a crush
这么多年
on Xiaoning for years?
你怎么知道的
Before they got married,
就结婚之前啊
Yuheng came to see
小纪单独找过一次
me and my husband once,
我跟筱柠她爸
telling us
意思就是
that he's serious
告诉我跟筱柠她爸
about Xiaoning.
他对筱柠啊是真心的
You didn't know?
你不知道吗
Boys
男孩子
don't share their thoughts with moms.
那点小心思不跟妈妈讲
That's perfectly normal.
那也正常
I don't blame him.
不怪昱恒
It was my fault.
是我的问题
This is my first time
这是我第一次
celebrating the festival away from home.
在外面过节
In the past,
以前呢
I always celebrated it with my parents.
过春节都是跟爸妈一起
This year, it's with both our families.
今年是咱们两家人
It's really wonderful.
真好
So, Ms Tu, how do you
那涂小姐觉得
feel about it?
怎么样啊
Even though we haven't registered yet,
虽然咱们两个没有领证
to be honest,
但说实话
this is the marriage life
这就是我想要的
I've always wanted.
婚后生活
Mom has been discharged.
妈出院了
Your financial burden
你的经济压力
has lightened a lot.
就小了很多
If I can secure
造船厂这一单
this shipyard contract,
要是签下来
I should be able to be made permanent.
我应该可以转正了吧
Then my salary will increase.
到时候工资就会高一些
We can save money together
我们两个一起攒钱
and take our parents on a trip.
带着爸妈出去旅游吧
Sure.
听你的
And you mentioned before
还有你之前
that you wanted to take me and mom
跟我说要带我跟妈
to visit dad's grave.
去给爸上坟
When are we going?
什么时候出发呀
After his father passed away,
他爸爸去世以后
I couldn't move on for a long time.
我很长时间都走不出来
I didn't show him
对他关心
much care.
很少
He went abroad for years,
他在国外这些年呢
and we grew even more distant.
我们就更疏远了
I feel like a
我是个
failure as a mother.
不合格的妈妈
If he had something on his mind,
那孩子有什么事
he's even less likely to share it.
就更不愿意跟我说了
Don't think that way.
别老这么想呀
We've got a huge family.
你看现在
How wonderful!
咱们一大家子人多好呀
So lively!
热热闹闹地
We can talk about anything.
想说什么说什么
Right?
是不是
It's all good.
好了 好了 好了
Dad's grave is
爸爸的墓啊
up in the mountains.
是在山上
This year, the festival came late.
今年咱们过节晚
By the time we go back,
等我们回去了
those trees
说不定
might
那些树上
have started to bud.
都已经开始抽芽了
Then we'll see
到时候就能看到
the mountains full of
满山的
spring scenery.
春景
Yuheng, Xiaoning.
昱恒 筱柠
Mom.
妈
I'm not interrupting you, am I?
我没有打扰你们吧
No, not at all.
没有
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
I bought
这个对戒呢
these rings
是
when Yuheng
昱恒在国外的时候
was abroad.
我买的
Because I thought
我当时就想未来
that one day,
有朝一日
if he found a girl he liked,
他有了喜欢的女孩子
I could give them to you as wedding gifts.
就送给你们做结婚礼物
I mentioned them to you before
之前我跟你们说过
that they were in my drawer.
在我抽屉里的
But you've never taken them.
但是你们一直也没拿
I didn't know the
我不知道你喜欢
style you like.
什么样的款式
You can wear it for now.
你先凑合戴
When it's time for your wedding,
等你们婚礼的时候啊
Yuheng can
让昱恒
buy you a nice diamond ring.
给你买个好的钻戒
It's
这个款式
really beautiful.
很好看
I like it.
我喜欢
Try it on.
试试看
OK.
好啊
It looks great.
好看吗妈
Thank you, mom.
谢谢妈
All this time,
一直以来
I've felt like a pretty inadequate mother.
妈妈都挺不称职的
Now that I see you get along,
现在看到你们这么好
I really have no regrets.
我真的就没什么遗憾了
What regrets, mom?
什么遗不遗憾的妈
Don't say such things during the New Year.
过年不能说这种话
Mom,
妈
I don't really trust his taste.
我呢不太相信他的眼光
Later,
等之后
I'll need you help choosing the ring.
挑钻戒的时候还得您挑
OK.
好
Mom,
妈
you'll definitely be healthy.
一定会健康平安的
What's on your mind?
想什么呢
Nothing.
没什么
Are you thinking that
是不是觉得
once you put on the ring,
戴上戒指以后
marriage isn't far off?
离结婚也就不远了
Dream on!
想得美
I was just trying to make mom happy.
我今天是为了哄妈高兴
Otherwise,
要不然啊
I wouldn't have let you
我才不会让你
put the ring on.
把戒指戴上
I've never agreed to marry you.
我可没有答应要嫁给你
I know.
我知道
I really like this ring.
我喜欢这个戒指
Once we get our marriage registered,
等我们俩领证了以后
we could wear rings.
可以戴戒指了
And I won't change it.
也不换
I'll just wear this one, OK?
就戴这个好不好
We need diamond rings as well.
钻戒也得要
Let's just stick with these.
就戴这个吧
Hey,
姐
if you're not asleep, come play cards!
没睡的话来打牌呀
Sure!
好啊
I can't sleep either.
正好我也睡不着
Can you help me check
你帮我看看
if the mark is still there?
我这个印还在不在
It's gone.
没了
I saw it this morning.
我今天早上
It was still there then.
看的时候还有呢
Now it's gone?
这么快就没了
Check for me.
帮我看看
What's up?
干吗
You're blushing.
脸红了
It's been over half an hour
你喝了酒都有
since you finished your drinks.
半个多小时了吧
The alcohol is just kicking in now?
酒劲刚上来呀
Do you think that with two moms around,
你真觉得两个妈妈在
I can't do anything about you?
我就拿你没办法了
Don't you mess around!
别胡来啊
They can't hear us from here.
在这他们就听不见了
It's 3:00 a.m.
三点了
Rao Jing!
饶静
Are you asleep?
你睡了
You...
你
You just fell asleep?
你就这么睡了
Alright, I'm leaving!
行 那我走了啊
It's not my house.
又不是我家
No matter how messy it is,
再脏 再乱
it's not my concern.
跟我也没什么关系
She's loaded; she can hire a cleaner.
她有钱自己请保洁
I'm not going to work for free.
我才不免费当劳动力
It's just not worth it.
不划算
Why is it getting colder?
这天怎么越睡越冷啊
Did I get wasted again?
又喝多了吗
I didn't even take off my robe.
睡袍都没脱
I'm so thirsty.
好渴啊
Why are you still here?
你怎么还在呢还没走
Well,
我那个
I was planning to leave,
我是准备走的
but I saw your place was a mess,
但我看你这屋子太乱了
so I tidied up.
我就顺便收拾一下
My place
我屋子
is messy?
还乱
Didn't I say
我不是说了
I would clean it myself?
自己会收拾的吗
I told you,
我都跟你说了
I'll do it myself.
我明天自己会收拾的
Here.
来
Let go.
撒手啊
Hey,
不是你
you were just cleaning.
打扫卫生
How come
怎么打扫得
you're blushing?
脸还红了呢
You're red all the way to your ears.
一直红到耳朵
Am I?
有吗 我这
It's the first day of the New Year.
我这新年的第一天
I'm full of good fortune.
我鸿运当头
Do you know how long
你知道我这一晚上
I've been cleaning your place?
给你收拾家收拾多久吗
How long?
收拾多久
All night?
一宿啊
You're not going home on New Year's day.
大过年的不回家
Instead,
在我家
you are cleaning my house.
给我打扫卫生
Do you
你不会
really have a crush on me?
真的看上姐了吧
If that's your New Year's wish,
如果这是你的新年愿望
I can almost help you make it happen.
我勉强可以帮你实现
My wish is to date
我的新年愿望呢
a few more cute guys.
是多约几个阳光弟弟
You?
你
You're too old for me.
太老了
What a coincidence!
巧了
My wish is
我的新年愿望啊
to date
是多几个
a few more cute girls.
可爱的妹妹
You?
你
You're not that young anymore.
不小了
So there's nothing
那就是
more to discuss?
没得聊了
There is.
有
If you could
如果你能
confess to me in tears,
哭着跟我表白
maybe
兴许啊
you still have a shot with me.
还能有点转机
The only thing that makes me cry
能让我饶静哭着说的
is a eulogy.
只有悼词
Whoa!
你狠
I'm not walking you out.
不送
So long.
拜拜
Don't dump trash on the first day
垃圾放门口别扔
of the New Year.
大年初一扔垃圾
It will bring bad luck.
会破财的
Where are my shoes?
我鞋呢
I understood.
我了解了
I will make sure to double-check
你说的这个情况
this situation you mentioned.
我会再认真确认一下
It's not a small matter after all.
毕竟不是一件小事
So I came to tell you
所以我知道的第一时间
as soon as I heard about it.
就赶紧来告诉你了
And
那
regarding my project?
我的这个项目
This company's
这家企业
qualifications are quite good.
资质还是不错的
I'll report to
我会先跟行里的领导
the higher-ups first.
汇报一下
If everything checks out,
如果可以的话
we can proceed with the loan application.
咱们再申报贷款
Yuhui, you've passed
小唐你现在
the probationary period.
正式过了试用期
Both your work performance
工作的成绩
and evaluations
以及考核的成绩
are satisfactory.
都还不错
You will officially become
等人事那边
the account manager
跟你聊完之后
in Section One
就可以正式成为
once all the HR formalities
咱们拓展一部的
are completed.
客户经理了
Congratulations in advance.
先恭喜你
Thank you.
谢谢师哥
Get to work now.
先去忙吧
Okay.
好
I'm almost done with the preparation.
我准备得差不多了
How did it go?
怎么样
Mr. Ji thinks it's not bad.
纪总认为还不错
It's being reviewed.
正在审核
Yuhui,
小唐
impressive!
真厉害
You just lost one client,
你这刚黄了一个客户
and another one came along.
又来一个客户
This quickly as well!
还这么快
Not only quickly,
不只是快
better quality too, this one is worth two.
质量更高 一个顶俩
Do you know
你们知道
who's her next client?
她下一个客户是谁吗
The Chunling Group!
春灵集团
Actually
其实吧
there were several banks
有好几个银行
had their eyes on this client.
都盯着这个客户呢
So I left Xihai
所以年前呢
right away
我就抓紧时间
before New Year.
离开了西海
And even had my dad
而且还托我爸
pull some strings.
牵了个线
This has even disrupted my vacation.
就为这事我年都没过好
But it's all good,
不过还好
the results are good.
结果是好的
What a pity!
我们羽卉辛苦了
Thank you for your hard work.
这个年都没过好
Your dad pulled some strings?
爸爸给牵的线
Not bad.
不错
Using every resource
动用身边
you have,
一切可用的资源
I like this way of getting
这种办事的方式啊
things done.
我喜欢
Xiaoning,
筱柠
you haven't submitted Mr. Yang's
杨总的那个贷款
loan application yet, have you?
你还没有提报吧
Mr. Ji is in a good mood now,
现在纪总心情好
you should keep it up!
你加油啊
I know.
我心里有数
Keep it up!
加油
Thanks, Jing.
好嘞 姐
Yes,
对
I'm coming over to you now.
我现在过去找你
Please look into the thing
刚刚跟你说的那个
I just told you about.
帮我查一下
It's Yang with the 'y',
木字旁的杨
remember.
记住了
Okay,
好
see you later.
那咱们一会儿见啊
Wait!
等一下
What a coincidence.
这么巧
Mr. Ji.
纪总
You're getting bolder.
胆子越来越大了
We have a camera here.
监控
No worries.
怕什么
This is the blind spot,
监控死角
they can't see.
看不见
Are you going out?
你要出去啊
I have to check out something.
有件事情要去查证一下
And you?
你呢
I'm going to lunch.
我去吃饭
Since you're free now,
正好现在有空
I have something to show you.
给你看个东西
The loan application
西海造船厂
of the Shipyard?
贷款申报
Yes.
嗯
This is some
这里面是
information on their company,
他们企业的相关资料
including operational conditions
有经营情况
and the financial reports.
还有财务报表
I hope Mr. Ji
希望纪总
will approve it soon,
看在我兢兢业业
considering my diligence
起早贪黑的份上
and hard work.
尽快通过
This is my first project.
这是我第一个项目
Don't worry,
你放心
I will give it my all
我一定会全力以赴
and do a good job.
把它做好的
Well,
对了
have the background checks
企业的背景调查那些
been confirmed?
确认了吗
The company's
企业
and the owner's credit history,
和老板征信
and all examinations
还有三查
have been done.
都已经确认过了
Don't be afraid of all the trouble.
别怕麻烦
Check them again.
再查查
Okay, Mr. Ji.
好的纪总
Goodbye.
我先走了纪总
Bye.
去吧
Do you know that death comes
懂不懂什么叫生于安乐
from ease and pleasure?
死于危难
I've always emphasized
我一直在跟你们强调
the importance of crisis awareness!
危机意识 危机意识
Did you just ignore it?
你们都给我当饭吃了
What is this Mr. Xing doing
这老邢大中午的
in the middle of the day?
发什么疯啊
If today
今天
they can
他们能在
outpace us
拓展客户的速度上
in client expansion,
超过我们
tomorrow, they'll be able to
明天他们就在
crush us in performance review!
业绩上能够敢碾压我们
Being stepped on
被纪昱恒那个空降兵
by Ji Yuheng,
踩在头上
even if you're not ashamed,
你们不觉得羞耻
I'm embarrassed for you!
我还觉得臊得慌呢
You,
你
go get the documents!
去把资料拿来
Wen,
小文
what's going on here?
你们二部什么情况啊
Not having lunch now,
大中午的不吃饭
is Mr. Xing conducting military exercises?
那老邢搞军事演习呢
Isn't it because of the pressure
还不是因为你们一部
from you guys?
给的压力
Mr. Xing was at a meeting this morning,
邢总上午去行里开会
and heard that you have
听说你们部门
a new girl named Yuhui with
来了一个姓唐的小姑娘
outstanding qualifications and experience.
能力履历没得说
She passed the probationary period,
不但通过了试用期
and has got the Chunling Group
还让春灵集团
to be your client.
成为你们贷款客户
He is in a crisis.
他这是有危机感了
I can't talk anymore,
不说了
I have to get the documents.
我要拿资料
She passed the probationary period?
小唐过试用期了
Ms Li,
李姐
I haven't seen you in days.
好几天没见到你了
Did you go back to your hometown?
回老家了
Yeah.
对呀
Your skin is looking better.
您皮肤是越来越好了
What have you been eating lately?
最近吃什么保养品了
You're quite the charmer.
就你嘴甜
Even the actresses
那天山童姥见了
would want to learn from you!
都得跟您请教请教
Here.
来
That's too much,
太多了
I won't even be able to finish it.
我都吃不完了
- Next. - Thank you.
来下一个 谢谢李姐
Must be lonely eating by yourself.
一个人吃饭很寂寞吧
Lonely?
寂寞
Of course.
当然寂寞了
I feel so bad that no one can share
那有 有好菜没人分享
this good food with me.
我多寂寞呀
Having chicken while
吃着鸡肉
looking at the muscular men
还看着视频里面的
in your phone,
肌肉小哥哥
isn't it too much?
不嫌腻啊
The old ones
这岁数大的呢
will be too much.
才叫腻
These young men just over
这二十多岁出头的
their 20s
弟弟吧
are very fresh.
清爽得很啊
Have you heard?
你听说了吗
Boss has turned in
老大把报告
the report.
提交上去了
Yuhui has passed.
小唐过试用期了
He really is something,
他真是啊
didn't leak anything.
一点风都不透出来
They're in such good shape!
这身材也太好了吧这
When I passed by
我刚才从二部
Section Two earlier,
经过的时候
Mr. Xing,
老邢
he's yelling.
他在那儿咆哮
Such a beautiful body!
这身材真好
He's taking Yuhui as a role model,
他拿小唐教育他们
telling
说
his people
你们呀
to learn from her,
要多跟小唐学习学习
and raise crisis awareness!
你们要有危机意识
If Yuhui
你说
got any better,
小唐再这么发展发展
even I would have that awareness.
我就要有危机意识了
Did you hear me?
你听我说了吗
Mr. Zhao,
我说赵经理
can you please shut up
你能不能闭上你的嘴
and leave me in peace with my phone?
让我安静看会手机行吗
Watch me have fun with him.
看我逗逗他
Just eat your meal.
你吃饭就吃饭
Fanggang.
赵哥
Stop talking so much.
废话那么多
You're here too.
你们也在这儿啊
You didn't see us
这都老大半天了
all this time?
这愣是没看见我们呗
No, I didn't.
没看见
Fanggang,
哥
why do you tell everything
你为什么一有什么事
to Jing first?
就先跟静姐汇报啊
Do I?
有吗
Is it true?
真有这回事
Are you sure?
你们确定
Then I need to ask Mr. Zhao.
那我倒要问问赵经理
Do you have any
你对于我是不是
special feelings for me?
有什么特殊情感啊
Of course.
当然有啊
You're the first person
我每早
I think about
一睁眼
when I open my eyes in the morning,
每晚睡觉前
and before I go to sleep at night.
我想的第一个都是你
I just wonder,
我就在想
Jing,
饶静
when are you going to
你到底什么时候
return my money?
还我钱啊
Boring.
没意思
Bummer.
下头
2,000 more.
再抵两千
No can do.
抵不了一点
500?
五百
Not even one.
一块都不行
Then I'll let you see
那我弟弟也给你看
these good men.
弟弟也给你看
No need.
我不需要
You've done so much
你为这个项目
for this project.
付出这么多
To be fair,
公事公办
you will be able to sign it.
也该由你签成功
I'm telling you,
你是不知道
I heard
这两天我在前台
that Tang Yuhui
听说那个唐羽卉
has signed some
好像签成了什么
new project.
新项目吧
She looked so arrogant,
走路那趾高气昂的劲儿
making me mistakenly
不知道以为
think that she's become the president.
她当行长了呢
You can't lose to her.
你可千万不能输给她
She was never
她从来
a competitor for my permanent position.
都不是我转正的对手
Plus I don't really want to
而且我也不想
compete with her.
跟她分一个高下呀
It's just that this project
只是因为这个项目
is crucial for me
对于我转正来说
to get changed.
非常关键
And I've fought hard
而且又是我自己
for it.
竞争来的
I'm always afraid any mistakes.
我总是害怕会出错
No worries.
不要怕
You've definitely got it.
你肯定没有问题的
Only you will always believe in me.
就你老觉得我没问题
I trust you.
就是没问题
Is Qi Yu's
齐郁那个
written test results out?
笔试成绩出来了吗
Not yet.
还没呢
He is very nervous.
他自己特别紧张
But I think it's really nothing.
但我觉得其实没什么呀
At worst, I'll just go head-to-head
大不了我就跟我爸
with my dad,
硬扛到底
or go behind his back
大不了就
and deal with
暗度陈仓
the consequences later.
先斩后奏
Then,
那
since I've done this before,
暗度陈仓的老前辈
I have to warn you...
就要叮嘱你一句
Wait a second,
等会儿
I've thought about it.
我想了一下
I won't be able to
你这个苦
handle your hardship.
我是吃不了的
Forget it.
算了 算了
Have a bite first!
你先 吃两口
C'mon!
吃两口啊
Don't disturb me.
别打扰我
I have to praise Yuhui.
另外要表扬一下小唐
Ever since
自从加入到
she joined us,
咱们部门之后啊
her performance has always been great.
成绩一直都很优秀
Especially, she's
尤其是这次
officially got the loan deal
春灵的贷款
with Chunling.
正式谈下来之后
It's truly good
作为一个业务新人来讲
for a newcomer.
成绩确实不错
Thank you, Mr. Ji.
谢谢纪总夸奖
I'll keep it up.
我继续加油
If there's anything
如果说接下来的
that you don't understand
推进过程当中
in the following procedures,
流程方面有什么不懂的
Xu Li,
许力
you should help her out more.
多帮帮她
Got it.
好嘞
Xiaoning,
小涂
come to my office.
来我办公室一趟
That's all.
散会吧
Xiaoning,
小涂
remember to explain
待会儿到办公室的时候
the necessity and advantages
把项目的必要性
of the project clearly to our boss.
还有优势跟他讲清楚
Don't be nervous.
别紧张
Just let me know when needed.
有事跟姐说啊
Xiaoning,
小涂
it's just a declaration.
申报而已没啥难度
Take it easy.
放轻松
Hold on and you'll get through it.
一鼓作气 蹚过去
Yeah.
对
The boss also knows
领导也知道
that this is your first declaration,
你是第一次申报
he won't be too hard on you.
不会太为难你的
Keep it up!
加油
Take it easy!
放松噢
Thank you.
谢谢
I got it.
知道了
You asked me this morning
上午你不是
to check it thoroughly, right?
让我好好查查吗
So I
我就把
checked again all the information
企业的所有资料
on the company,
又重新查了一遍
including that on their employees
还包括他们企业员工
and their clients.
还有企业客户的
All done.
我都查了一遍
Stop doing
这个项目
this project.
别再跟了
What do you mean?
什么意思呀
To be honest,
说实话
this project
这个项目
won't be able to apply for a loan.
没办法申请贷款
So you need to hurry and find another one.
所以抓紧时间找新的
Why?
为什么
What's wrong?
出现什么问题了
Mr. Yang has been in prison,
杨总他之前进去过
he has a record.
他有案底
The ordinary examinations
有的企业
are far from enough
如果只做三查
with some companies.
是远远不够的
Because they
早期有过案底的人
won't show
在三查里
any prison record from long ago.
是显示不出来的
Of course,
当然了
very few people know
他进去过这件事情
about his time in prison.
很少有人知道
There have been rumors before
所以之前一直都有传言
that he didn't apply for a loan
说杨总不贷款
not 'cause he's unwilling,
并不代表着他不愿意贷
but 'cause he's not qualified.
而是他贷不了
Then,
所以
go hurry and find another project.
抓紧时间找其他的项目
Don't get discouraged.
别灰心啊
I won't.
不会
But
但
I need some time.
但是我需要缓一下
Xiaoning, why that face?
筱柠什么表情
Failed?
没过吗
Didn't I tell you to
我不是让你好好
explain to him clearly?
跟他讲吗
It's not possible.
不可能吧
I've looked through the documents.
这资料我之前翻过
All okay.
没有问题啊
I don't understand.
我就纳了闷了
This project was overseen
小涂这西海镇的项目
by the boss himself.
是领导亲自坐镇的
How can the declaration
怎么这个申报就
not be passed?
没通过呢
You're right.
是啊
It shouldn't be.
不应该啊
Maybe there's...
是不是哪一块有
Get back to work.
回去工作吧
I'll go ask
我去问问看
and find out more.
是什么情况
Hello, Mr. Liu.
喂 刘总
Yeah,
对
all good.
一切顺利
I'll send the details of the contract
我稍后把合同细节
to you later.
同步给您
Okay.
好的
It's just a small project.
丢了一个小项目而已
You just started
刚开始吗
doing this and have no experience.
大家没有经验
This is normal.
筱柠姐
Don't feel too bad.
你别太难受了
No,
没有啊
I don't feel bad.
我没有不高兴
It's okay.
还行
I'm fine.
挺好的
Actually,
其实你的项目
the due diligence of your project
尽调本来应该
should've been done by you.
是你来做的
But I was afraid
但是我怕
that you would've made a mistake,
你在这上面栽跟头
so I did some more for you.
所以就帮你多做了一点
You did the research?
是你去调查的
Yeah!
对呀
Yuheng didn't tell you?
师哥没跟你说呀
Maybe he's worried you'll be embarrassed.
他可能怕你尴尬吧
After all you've been here
毕竟你来拓展部的时间
longer than me.
比我要久
It wouldn't be appropriate for me
这事要是被我先发现了
discover this first.
确实不太合适
How did you figure it out?
你是怎么发现问题的
Yang Jie,
小杨哥
could you talk to Mr. Yang
你能不能跟杨总
some more?
再说说想想办法呀
Yuhui,
羽卉
I've already tried my best.
我已经尽力了
Have a drink.
喝酒
But this loan is very important to me.
但这笔贷款对我很重要
He is my first client.
他是我第一个客户
I can't lose it to anyone else.
我不能输给其他人
This loan probably
我干爹的贷款啊
won't get approved.
可能办不下来的
What do you mean?
办不下来是什么意思啊
I'm grateful to you
你给我介绍了
for introducing me
新的销售渠道
to a new sales channel.
我很感谢你
As your friend,
作为朋友
I hope you can understand
我希望你能明白一点
that a setback may turn out
塞翁失马
to be a blessing in disguise.
焉知非福啊
Let's drink.
喝酒吧
Let it go.
别想了
As account managers,
咱们做客户经理的
if we lacked even this level
要是连这点职业敏感度
of professional sensitivity,
都没有的话
then we might not be
那可能确实
well-suited for this line of work.
不太适合这一行
Alright,
对了
by the way.
我还没恭喜你呢
Congratulations!
恭喜你啊
Thank you!
谢谢
Xu Li,
许力
what's up?
怎么了
I'm about to go home.
我准备回家呢
I don't have
啤酒厂的资料
the brewery's documents.
没在我这儿啊
Rao Jing has them.
在饶静那儿怎么了
You scared me.
吓我一跳
Why are you here?
你怎么来了
I'm here for the brewery's documents.
我来拿啤酒厂的资料
I'm leaving right away.
拿了就走
You even put on perfume?
你拿资料还喷香水啊
I...
我
wanna be an elegant working man.
想当个精致的打工仔
Is there a problem with that?
有问题吗
Not at all.
没错
Wait a second.
你等一下啊
Throw this out for me, please.
麻烦这个帮我丢一下
Um, do you want to
算了你要不要
wait inside?
进来等会儿
It's none of my business.
跟我有什么关系
It's not my house.
又不是我家
It's not like
搞得好像
I care about her a lot.
我很在乎她似的
I can't look at this anymore.
实在是看不下去了
How can she not wash
你也不知道把这些衣服
all these clothes?
拿去洗了呢
There are so many.
这么多件
I left an annex
还有一份附件
at the bank.
落在银行了
If you're in a hurry
你要是着急的话
you'll need to pick it up.
你得去取一趟
What are you doing?
拿我衣服干吗
Don't misunderstand.
你别误会了啊
I'm not taking care of you.
我没有要照顾你
I just couldn't look at them anymore.
我是实在看不下去了
I have germophobia.
我有洁癖
If it's true,
你要是有这个爱好
why are you an account manager?
你干什么客户经理
You should've been a janitor.
你应该当保洁
Earn money while pursuing your hobby.
赚钱爱好两不误啊
You have a point.
有道理
Then I'll use your house
那我准备就拿你家
as a trial run.
做试工点
I'll give you 50% off.
我给你打个半折吧
Do you know about the situation
这个啤酒厂老板的情况
of the owner of the brewery?
你知道吧
He worked at the
他之前在那个
Dajiang Brewery before.
大江啤酒工作过
Then,
后来呢
he worked at
在奥古特的啤酒厂
the Augerta Brewery.
也工作过
After, he quit
然后就辞去了工作
and went to Shanghai.
去上海打拼
I'll get lunch for you for 3 days,
帮忙打三天饭
and an afternoon tea
加楼下小卖部
from the store downstairs.
下午茶一顿
No more than that.
不能再多了啊
The accuracy rate
我们班数学
of the math summer homework
暑假作业的正确率
worth only that much?
才值这个钱
Xiaoning and I haven't finish it yet.
我和筱柠都还没做完
Do you think the accuracy rate
你觉得对我们来说
is what's important to us?
重要的是正确率吗
The important thing is,
重要的是
we go back to school today.
今天返校
The class starts tomorrow.
明天开学
We have to turn in all the homework.
就得上交完整作业了
Give it to me.
快给我
No, no way.
不行 不行
I'll lend it to you,
我借给你
for free.
不用钱
Which class is this math homework from?
这数学是哪个班的呀
There are several solutions
一道题有好几种
to a question.
解决方法
So hardworking!
这么拼的呀
Math is in the first class.
数学一班
English is in the second class.
英语二班
Geology is in the third class.
地理三班
Didn't even write their name.
也不写个名
What a good nameless hero!
谢谢这个无名英雄